For labelling a map or diagram, many students
make mistakes due to carelessness, leading to misspellings
or not checking the answers
against what they
predicted.
Sometimes students also struggle
to get the correct
answers because they do not know some words
or they're not sure how to spell them.
Another common mistake is that students fail to
recognise when distractors use the wrong voice, for
example active vs passive, compared to what the
recording actually states.
To improve IELTS listening skills, you need to
expand your vocabulary.
For labelling a map, vocabulary of direction is
really important.
You have to remember some phrases such as,
next to, west or east of something, turn
east, west, left or right, behind, turn right
of, turn left of, go straight on, opposite,
go past, or go beyond.
Another thing you should remember is that you
should be well prepared for everything before listening,
because this can provide you with all the
clues that will help you listen in an
active and attentive way.
Prediction helps us make wiser decisions.